<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jon Daniel]]></title>
  <link href="http://jondaniel.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jondaniel.net/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-27T14:41:57-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://jondaniel.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jon Daniel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Respecting The Zone]]></title>
    <link href="http://jondaniel.net/blog/2012/12/20/respecting-the-zone/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T17:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jondaniel.net/blog/2012/12/20/respecting-the-zone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All good developers are able to get into &#8220;The Zone&#8221;. This is a state of mind
where nothing matters but you and the code. Your office, your friends on IRC,
even the music in your ears all cease to be and your mind is envisioning the
raw logic of the problem you are trying to solve. It&#8217;s almost euphoric. That is
until a nerf dart hits you in the back of the head because someone is trying to
get your attention.</p>

<p>Honestly I find this behavior to be not only disrespectful but downright rude.
Yes we&#8217;ve all been in a situation where we need to get a hold of someone and
they are unresponsive, it sucks, but unless there is a serious emergency (I&#8217;m
talking downtime, significant lost of income, building on fire, etc) &#8220;The Zone&#8221;
should be respected. Violently disengaging someone from the work is rather
disorienting and after every disengagement it makes it just a little bit more
difficult to get going again.</p>

<p>As developers it&#8217;s our job to solve difficult problems. Every minute we spend
out of &#8220;The Zone&#8221; our talents are essentially being wasted. Sure there is always
&#8220;meta-work&#8221; that needs to be done (e-mail, meetings, standups, etc) but we
should all do our part to keep everyone on the team productive.</p>

<p>In turn we as developers must show respect back. Set a timer to go off ever 25
minutes reminding us to take a break and disengage ourselves from our euphoric
state (known as the pomodoro technique). Use this time to checkup on e-mail,
help coworkers with problems, ask questions, take a walk, etc. Your time in
&#8220;The Zone&#8221; tends to lose meaning if your coworkers never see you in any other way.</p>

<p><strong>TLDR</strong>: Don&#8217;t shoot developers with nerf darts. It makes them angry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Year In Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://jondaniel.net/blog/2012/12/20/year-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T14:54:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://jondaniel.net/blog/2012/12/20/year-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>2013 is almost here! Another year past, another year older (and maybe a tiny bit
wiser). 2012 was a pretty interesting year for me professionally. Lots of ups, lots
of downs, and plenty of things in between.</p>

<p>This year marks my first full year as a Ruby developer and it markes the first time an
employer has considered me a &#8220;Senior Developer&#8221;. Thinking of myself as even
remotely experienced makes my head spin. In my mind I&#8217;m still the clueless
Computer Science student who is terrified of not being able to make it in the
<strong>real world</strong>.</p>

<p>Steel City Ruby Conf was the first programming oriented conference I attended
and I had a blast. While I wasn&#8217;t nearly as social as I was hoping I still
got to meet a ton of great people and hear talks from some of my personal
&#8220;ruby heros&#8221; like <a href="https://twitter.com/tenderlove">Aaron Patterson</a> and
<a href="https://twitter.com/coreyhaines">Corey Haines</a>. I was really looking forward to
<a href="https://twitter.com/jimweirich">Jim Weirich</a>&#8217;s talk but due to a pretty nasty
migraine I had to leave early.</p>

<p>Unfortunately I no longer see former coworkers
<a href="https://twitter.com/Hoffm">Michael Hoffman</a> and
<a href="https://twitter.com/laurenvoswinkel">Lauren Voswinkel</a> on a day-to-day basis
but they both moved on to bigger and better things. Michael moved to New York
City to be a rockstar developer and Lauren seems to be on the &#8220;ruby hero in training&#8221;
path so I wish them both the best of luck.</p>

<p>I made my first contribution to the Ruby Programming Language this year. <a href="https://github.com/ruby/ruby/pull/173">Pull
Request #173</a> was a small fix I made to
the IPAddr standard library to make some job processing recover from errors a
bit more effectively. My contributions are going to be included with Ruby 2.0
so it&#8217;s pretty exciting to know that programmers all over the world will be
using a tiny bit of my code.</p>

<p>One of my goals for 2012 was to overcome some of my shyness and social anxiety,
epically in a professional setting. This was a bit of a mixed bag because I
still have problems talking to people I&#8217;m unfamiliar with (and accepting that
I&#8217;m not clueless when it comes to programming). I was able to give 2 talks at
Pittsburgh Ruby Brigade meetings this year. One on Continuous Integration and the other
on Liquid Markup. The CI talk went pretty poorly but that was because I was
far more unprepared than I though (a common problem of mine when speaking). When
I agreed to give a talk on Liquid Markup I made it my goal to not let history
repeat itself. I got some pretty brutally honest feedback on my Liquid talk but
the general consensus was that my talk went well.</p>

<h2>Moving Forward</h2>

<p>2013 looks like it&#8217;s going to be a pretty exciting year. Work has been going
well (hopefully more on that later), I have made some pretty awesome new friends,
and I have a lot of renewed enthusiasm for my profession.</p>

<h3>Goals for 2013</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>Maintain a technical blog. I don&#8217;t need to post every day (or even every week)
but I want to keep a record of my thoughts, successes, and failures relating
to my craft.</p></li>
<li><p>Remain involved with the tech community. This year saw the end of my
involvement with the PHP User Group, but I became more involved with the Ruby
community. I&#8217;d like to step up this involvement a bit by giving a few more talks and attending a few more conferences.</p></li>
<li><p>Learn a new programming language. I&#8217;ve been working in mostly Ruby and
JavaScript during my employment at Webkite. I&#8217;d like to pickup and become
comfortable with a new language, I&#8217;m looking at you Go.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
