<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: officelife | Jon Daniel]]></title>
  <link href="http://binarycleric.github.com/blog/categories/officelife/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://binarycleric.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-01T23:27:04-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://binarycleric.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jon Daniel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Respecting The Zone]]></title>
    <link href="http://binarycleric.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/respecting-the-zone/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T17:32:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://binarycleric.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/respecting-the-zone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>All good developers are able to get into "The Zone". This is a state of mind
where nothing matters but you and the code. Your office, your friends on IRC,
even the music in your ears all cease to be and your mind is envisioning the
raw logic of the problem you are trying to solve. It's almost euphoric. That is
until a nerf dart hits you in the back of the head because someone is trying to
get your attention.</p>

<p>Honestly I find this behavior to be not only disrespectful but downright rude.
Yes we've all been in a situation where we need to get a hold of someone and
they are unresponsive, it sucks, but unless there is a serious emergency (I'm
talking downtime, significant lost of income, building on fire, etc) "The Zone"
should be respected. Violently disengaging someone from the work is rather
disorienting and after every disengagement it makes it just a little bit more
difficult to get going again.</p>

<p>As developers it's our job to solve difficult problems. Every minute we spend
out of "The Zone" our talents are essentially being wasted. Sure there is always
"meta-work" that needs to be done (e-mail, meetings, standups, etc) but we
should all do our part to keep everyone on the team productive.</p>

<p>In turn we as developers must show respect back. Set a timer to go off ever 25
minutes reminding us to take a break and disengage ourselves from our euphoric
state (known as the pomodoro technique). Use this time to checkup on e-mail,
help coworkers with problems, ask questions, take a walk, etc. Your time in
"The Zone" tends to lose meaning if your coworkers never see you in any other way.</p>

<p><strong>TLDR</strong>: Don't shoot developers with nerf darts. It makes them angry.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
